H-01 will replace you NEXT,
Ｈ01は君達ＮＥＸＴに代わり
and will be Heroes in this city.
ヒーローとしてこの街に君臨する
新たな時代が到来するのだ！
A new age will begin!
You call this thing a Hero?
こいつがヒーローだと
You can fight him together if you want.
さあ 二人掛かりで構いません
Unless you defeat H-01, you cannot protect anything.
Ｈ01を倒さぬ限り君達は何も守る事は
できない　市民も 仲間も
The people of this city, your friends, or your daughter.
君の娘も
Kaede...
楓
But I'll save just one of you.
君達の中で一人だけ命を
助けてあげましょう
The quickest one wins.
早いもの勝ち
If you want to be saved,
助かりたければ首輪に設置されている
解除スイッチを押したまえ
flip the deactivation switch on your collar.
However, once you do, everyone else will blow up.
スイッチを押した瞬間！
他の奴らの爆弾は爆発するがね
You have until Tiger and Barnaby are defeated by H-01.
制限時間はタイガーアンドバーナビーが
Ｈ01に倒されるまで
The moment they lose,
敗北した瞬間
誰かがスイッチを押していなくても
everyone will blow up even if no one ﬂipped their switch.
君達全員の爆弾はドカーン！
Let's go.
行くぞ
Right.
ええ
yabureta PAGE wa ubawaretanda yo
That torn page was stolen,
破れたページは
奪われたんだよ
dokoka de otoshita oboe wa nai kara
since I don't remember ever dropping it anywhere.
何処かで落とした
覚えはないから
iwakan mo nai hodo kirei ni nai soko ni wa
In the place where the page used to be,
違和感もないほど
綺麗にないそこには
yume to iu nano shou ga tashikani atta
there was a chapter entitled "Dreams."
夢という名の章が確かにあった
nani wo nikumeba ii? kako ka jibun jishin ka
But who should I blame? The past? Myself?
何を憎めばいい？
過去か自分自身か
dekireba hoka no dareka de are
If possible, I hope it's someone else.
出来れば他の誰かであれ
monogatari no bokura ga sono mirai wo omou no wa
We, the characters in the story, think of the future.
物語の僕らが
その未来想うのは
nakushita ato demo shuyaku wa kawarenai kara
Because even after we're gone, the main character can't change.
失くした後でも
主役は変われないから
shousan nante sarenakutatte tashikana kyou ga aru nara
Even if I'm not praised, as long as today is here,
賞賛なんてされなくたって
確かな今日があるなら
yume nante namae no shou wa ikura demo tsukurerunda
I can make as many chapters as I want entitled "Dreams."
夢なんて名前の章は
いくらでも創れるんだ
Tiger...
タイガー
We're counting on you two.
頼むわよ そんな奴やっつけて
助けてちょうだい
Beat that thing and save us.
Don't bother with such foolish expectations.
愚かな期待など お捨てなさい
彼らがＨ01を下す可能性など皆無
それは君達も分かっているでしょう
They cannot win against H-01. And you know it.
さあ 早くご決断を
Now, make your decision!
None of us will give in to you!
貴様らに屈する者などいない！
ふんっ
Do you really believe that?
本当にそうですかな
いつ誰が裏切るか分りませんよ
Someone could betray you at any time.
んっ
Hang on, Kaede.
待ってろよ 楓
I'll save you right away!
すぐに助けてやるからな
はあーっ！
だっ えっ！
We need more time.
まだ時間が
Damn it!
だっ！　なら能力無しでも！
Then I'll do this even without my powers.
待ってください！
Wait!
But Kaede is...!
いや でも楓が！
うえっ！
Look out!
危ない！
うわっ！
What the heck was that?
何だよ 今の
We don't stand a chance without our powers.
やはり能力無しじゃ無謀ですよ
We have to hold out until we recover, huh?
回復するまで しのぐしかねえのか
ぐわっ！
Pull yourselves together, guys!
おいおい しっかりしろ！
気の毒な奴らですね
I almost feel sorry for them.
They can only use their powers for a limited amount of time.
能力の使用に制限があるなんて
H-01, on the other hand, can use his power indefinitely.
Ｈ01は永久にその力を操れるというのに
I'll show you a sub-human NEXT who's superior.
人間崩れのＮＥＸＴに どちらが
優れた存在か 思い知らせてやりますよ
ぐわっ！
どあっ！
What are you doing?
何だよ パチパチ
アンドロイドは元々バーナビーの
両親によりディベロップされたものでね
That android was originally developed by Barnaby's parents.
おう
人間に危害を加えようとすると
It should be programmed to shut down if it harms any humans.
シャットダウンのプログラムコードが
走るはずなんだ
んん ん！
But seeing that it can attack the Heroes,
だがヒーロー達を
攻撃したところをみると
恐らくセーフティデバイスが
何らかの細工でブロックされている
they must have somehow blocked its safety device.
だから 今
So I'm trying to get the password to make it reboot.
リブートするためのパスワードを…
分かった？
Do you understand?
良く分かんねーよ
Not really!
Why isn't the show resuming?!
なぜ番組は放送を再開せんのだ
And we're still unable to contact the Heroes!
ヒーローとの連絡も途絶えたままだぞ
Mr. Mayor!
市長 この非常時にマーべリックさんは
どこにいるんです？
Where has Mr. Maverick gone to at a time like this?
Umm... W-Well...
いや そ それは
What do you think you're doing?!
ちょっとどう言うつもりよ
あんた殺人犯をかばう気？
You plan on defending that murderer?!
No.
否 私はタナトスの声に
I only obey...
...the voice of Thanatos.
従うまで
貴様の正体はいずれ明らかにしてやる
I shall uncover your identity soon.
Along with the mastermind behind all of this.
黒幕と共にな
えっ え！
What?
あっ
ん
Thank you for your patience, gentlemen.
お待たせしました
You're late, Mr. Maverick!
おお！　遅いですよマーべリックさん
みんな あなたを待って
We were all waiting for you.
申し訳ありません
ヒーローから連絡があったもので
My apologies.
I just finished speaking with the Heroes.
ぬっ
The Heroes are currently putting their efforts
彼らは今 あるテロ組織の鎮圧に
力を尽くしています
to bring down a terrorist group.
えっ 何！　何だと！
What?
They're responsible for this situation?
そいつらがこの状況を？
Yes.
ええ
Is this going to be like the time Jake attacked the city?!
まさか またジェイクのように
So are the Heroes all right?
それでヒーロー達は無事なのか？
They are in a very tough situation,
戦況は非常に厳しいと言えます
but they are working hard to defend this city.
ですが 彼らは必至にこの街を
守ろうと戦っている
We must believe in our Heroes and wait for their return!
今 我々ができる事はヒーローを
信じて待つこと それだけです
ん
はあ はあ はあ
Here it comes.
来ますよ
Huh?
ええっ！
うえっ
Damn!
だっ！
If this keeps up,
こんなんじゃ
能力出す前にやられちまう
we're going to be defeated before we can use our powers!
Even those two are no match?
あの二人でも敵わないの
あっ
くっ
はあ
あっ
At this rate, they'll...
このままじゃあいつらは
えっ
Push it. Hurry up and push it!
押せ 早く押せ
くっ
くあっ
ぐあっ
はあはあ
Drat! You coward!
かーっ！　臆病者が
What should I do?
どうすればいい スカイハイ
ん？
What should I do?
どうすれば
あはは
ふふ ふふふ
If one of us survived, it would be better than if we all perished.
このままヒーローが全滅するよりは
誰か生き残った方が
なっ
You plan to betray us?!
あんた 裏切るつもり？
You're kidding, right?
嘘でしょ？
No, that's not true!
違う！　違う！
That's not what I meant!
誤解だ！　おい みんな！
Wait! Guys!
さあ どうします みなさん
So, what now, Heroes?
Is he serious?
あいつ本気かよ
Mr. Sky High!
スカイハイさん
No... He wouldn't!
そんな まさか
Yes, that's right. Think about it.
悩め悩め
Because of my words, everyone...
私の言葉で みんなが
See? That's the limit of your so-called friendship.
所詮そんなものだ
貴様らの信頼など
ん？
Ah, you don't have much time left.
ああ！　タイムリミットまであと僅か
逃げ回るのは限界のようですね
They're unable to run around for much longer.
ええ くそーっ！
Damn it!
Come on, hurry up and push the button.
さあ 早くボタンを押すのです
Stop it... Stop it!
やめろ やめろ！
Someone might push it as I speak.
今にも誰かが押すかもしれない
Please, no more!
もうやめてよ！
You are all rivals to begin with.
元々あなた達はライバルなのですよ
いつ裏切るか分らない
You never know when someone will betray you.
Rivals...
ライバル
さあ 早く！
Come on, hurry!
うっ
The one who's most vulnerable at time like this would be...
こう言う時 一番危ないのは
おい スカイハイ 本気かよ！
おい
Hey! Sky High! Are you serious?! Hey!
Those poor things.
哀れな奴らだ
ボタンを押せば全員死ぬとも知らずに
They don't know that they'll all die if they push their buttons.
端から貴様らが助かる道など無いわ
化けものＮＥＸＴめ
I was never going to let you live, you NEXT freaks!
What should I do, Tiger?
どうしたらいいの？
タイガー
どおっはーっ
Kotetsu!
虎徹さん！
どわっ
ぐわっ
うっ うっ
はあ はあ えっ
Is this it for us?
もう 終わりか
Take care of Kaede if anything happens to me.
俺に何かあったら楓を頼む
えっふっ
ぬおーっ！
はあ はあ はあ はあ…
Come on, do it! Come on!
さあ行け！
さあ
ん！
だーっ！はあ
くっ
えっ
Our powers are back!
能力が！
All right, let's go!
よっしゃー！
行っくぜー！
はあーっ！
んーなっ
へあっ！
へっ
どあっ
You bastard!
こーのっ！
うえっ なんつーパワーだ
What power...
ぐう
ぐえ
つあーっ！
んあー痛って
どうわーっ！
Kotetsu!
虎徹さん！
Everything is going according to my plan.
すべて私の計画通りだ
It looks like things are going well.
順調なようだね
Yes.
ええ 能力を発動したところで
スピード パワー
Even with their powers activated,
my H-01's speed and strength are on a whole different level.
すべてにおいて次元が違う
そろそろ無能なＮＥＸＴ共を
一掃致しましょう
I believe it's time to rid of these pathetic NEXT.
I have just finished making the necessary arrangements.
こちらも手筈は整えた
ヒーロー達は全員
名誉の戦死として処理される
Their deaths will be handled as
dying honorably in the line of duty.
ぐふっ
だーっ
うえいっ
へあっ
おっ
貴様らの攻撃では 傷一つ付けられんよ
Your attacks can't put a single scratch on him.
ああ
Damn it!
くそーっ
えっ
Now!
今です！
Got it.
分かってるよ！
Good Luck Mode!
Good Luck Mode
おあーっ
へあーっ
はーっ
Three...
Two...
One...
Tiger & Bunny.
TIGER ＆ BUNNY
OVER ＆ OUT！
Over and Out!
えいっ
We did it!
よっしゃーっ！
あっ
What?
こいつ
ぬっ
どわっ
へあーっ
えっ
やっ
ぐわっ
ぐあっ
Bunny!
バニー
えっ
どわっ
ぐっ
んっ
どわっ
うっ
Stop it...
やめろ…
That's enough, you bastard!
えー加減にしろよ
このヤロー！
くはっ
へあーっ
どあーっ
がっ
ぐわっ
Kotetsu...
虎徹…
We won't let things end here...
こんなところで終ってたまるか
We can't afford to lose to you!
俺達やられるわけには いかねーんだよ
へっ
へあーっ！
あっ はあ
んっ んっ
どわっ
ああ…
だーっ
あっ はあ
えっ くっ あっ
ぬあっ へっ
はあ えっ
I've made up my mind!
決めた
Oh, how unfortunate for you all.
あっらー みなさん残念だ
ブルーローズが心を決めたようですよ
Blue Rose has made up her mind.
ぬあっ
あっ
はっ
さ ブルーローズ 早くボタンを
Now, Blue Rose, push the button.
I won't push it.
私は押さない
What?
何！
I believe in everyone.
私はみんなを信じてるから
はっ
I believe in Tiger and Barnaby.
タイガーとバーナビーを信じてるから
Is that all you wanted to say?
そんな くだらない事を言うために
Everyone! Those two would never lose.
みんな あの二人が負ける訳ないじゃない
あっ
んっ んっ
We know them.
あの二人の事 分かってたら
こんな決断必要ない
There's no reason for us to make a choice!
はあ
へっ
As a Hero, I'll trust my friends until the very end.
私はヒーローとして最後まで
仲間を信じる　そう決めたの
That's what I've decided.
I want to believe in Mr. Tiger and Barnaby too.
僕もタイガーさん達を信じたい
あの二人なら絶対勝ってくれるよ
I know those two will win!
You're right.
そうよね
What good is a Hero if he can't believe in his own friends?!
仲間を信じられなくて
何がヒーローだよ
Yeah.
だよな そうなんだよ
なのに俺は…
That's right. And yet, I...
Thank you, Blue Rose. And thank you again!
ありがとう ブルーローズ
そして ありがとう！
うふっ
Oh, please... Trust? Heart? Pathetic!
あー 生温い　何が“信じる”だ
何が“心”だ
ふっふ
Go, H-01! Slice those fools!
さあ Ｈ01
そんな奴ら切り刻んでしまえ
んっ はあ んっ
ぐわっ ぐわーっ
だっ
Damn it... Our attacks won't work...
くそ！攻撃が
あっ
えっ えっ
だあっ
ぶあっ
あっ
くっ
Kotetsu?
虎徹さん
Now, Bunny!
今だ バニー
それでこいつをやれ
Take this thing down with that!
What?
ええっ
あっ
What about you?!
でもあなたが
Don't worry about me! I'll dodge it before it hits.
心配すんな
当たる直前で俺はよける
But!
でも！
I'll be all right.
大丈夫だって
くっ えっ ぬっ
だーっ 早く撃て！
Hurry up and fire it.
えっ
はあ はあ
Hurry, Bunny!
早くしろバニー！
んっ んえっ
へあーっ
えっ はあ はあ はあ
うっ
おっ
あっ
おあ
わー
They did it!
やった
Wow!
わーお
How?! How could my H-01 lose?!
なぜだ！　なぜ私のＨ01が
げっ はあ
I'll kill them...
殺してやるこんなＮＥＸＴ共！
I'll kill those NEXT!
んっ がはっ
んんっ
You?
お前
I'm the daughter of Wild Tiger!
私だって
ワイルドタイガーの娘なんだから
Stay away!
来ないで！
ぐはっ
That's my...
私の…
うはっ ううう
ああっ ああ…
Oh!
あらっ
Thanks, Kaede dear!
サンクス 楓ちゃん
ええっ
んっ
Fire!
ファーイヤー！
えあっ しゃーっ
All right!
えっ
Let's go!
行くぞ！
We did it, Kotetsu!
やりましたね 虎徹さん
Kotetsu?
虎徹さん？
あ
あっ
What's wrong?
どうしたんですか
ぬああ…
あっ
ぶわっ
ええっ
ぬあ
あ わりい 当たっちまった
Sorry, I got hit.
What?
え
Now, Bunny!
今だ バニー
やっぱ能力無しじゃ よけきれねえな
I guess it's hard to dodge without my powers.
えへへ 参ったよ こんな大事な時に
Damn. And it had to happen during our only chance.
どうして能力切れてるんですか？
だってまだ時間は
Why have your powers run out?
You still have time left.
To tell you the truth, my power can barely last for four minutes.
あー 実はな
俺の力もう４分持たねーんだよ
ええ！
It's been declining.
減退ってやつ？
No... When did this happen?
そんな いつから？
うあ あっ もう何ヶ月かなあ
For several months now.
あっ くっ
隠すの苦労したんだぞ
It was tough trying to keep it a secret from you.
どうしてそんな大事な事を
僕に言ってくれなかったんです
Why didn't you tell me something so important?!
Because you'd worry about me.
余計な心配すんだろ お前
Is that why you said you're going to quit being a Hero?
だから ヒーロー辞めるって
What's this about quitting?
どう言う事なんです
ヒーロー辞めるって
Being a Hero is unsteady.
ヒーロー業って不規則だろ
It's fine when you're still young,
若いうちはいいけど
年取ると堪えんだよ
but as you get older it starts to get to you.
くっ すみません
虎徹さんがそんな状態なのに
I'm sorry, Kotetsu.
I never realized what condition you were in.
気が付かなくて
You idiot.
バカ 気付かれちゃ意味ねーんだよ
隠してんだから
What's the point of hiding it if you notice it?
ぶおっ おほっ
あっ
うっ あっ ちょっとヤバいかも
Damn... I think this is bad...
もう 喋らないでください
Stop talking already.
なあ バニー
Say, Bunny...
I said, stop!
だから もう…
It was fun going after criminals with you,
犯人一緒に追い掛けたり
お前に説教されたり 楽しかったよ
and listening to your silly lectures...
When you started calling me "Kotetsu,"
お前が“虎徹さん”って
呼んでくれた時なんか
I got so happy that I went out drinking by myself.
嬉しくって 何か 一人で
飲みに行ったりして はは
Stop talking like that!
そんな話 やめてください！
Thanks for everything.
今まで ありがとな
Shut up!
やめてくださいよ！
何 死にそうになってるんですか！
Don't talk like you're about to die!
You're not that kind of person.
こんな人じゃないでしょう
あなた元気だけが取り柄のはずでしょ！
Your enthusiasm is your only strong point, right?!
いつか虎徹さんに 僕のチャーハンを
食べてもらおうと思って
I've been learning how to make fried rice!
So you have to try it some day!
練習してるんですからね！
あー うっ
Kotetsu!
虎徹さん！
Too close, pal...
ちけーよ おい
お前 まつ毛なげーんだな
Hey, you have pretty long eyelashes...
Kotetsu?
虎徹さん
Kotetsu!
虎徹さーん！
灰色に染まる街の片隅で
hai iro ni somaru machi no katasumi de souzou dake no yume wo miteita
In an obscure corner of the ashen city, I was having a surreal dream.
想像だけの夢をみていた
存在する事の意味を
sonzai suru koto no imi wo nantonaku kangaehajimeta
I started to think about the meaning of existence.
なんとなく考え始めた
But I never know
BUT, I NEVER KNOW.
But, I never know.
myself＆夢＆
MYSELF AND yume AND TRUE AND ANYMORE
Myself & dreams & truth & anymore.
true＆Anymore
もう… もっと…
mou... motto...
At all...
こんな世界で私に聞いたの
konna sekai de watashi ni kita no ittai nani ga dekiru no ka wo
I asked myself what one can do in a world like this.
一体何が出来るのかを
あなたの笑顔が教えてくれたような
anata no egao ga oshiete kureta youna sonna kigashita kara
And I felt that your smiling face could teach me the answer.
そんな気がしたから
光を見つけたような
hikari wo mitsuketa youna itami ni furerareru
And enabled me to be touched by the pain of finding light.
痛みに触れられる
そう そんな気がした
sou, sonna kigashita
Yes, that was the feeling.
人は皆儚い夢を
hito wa mina hakanai yume wo kono te ni ireru tame ni
In pursuing their fleeting dreams,
この手に入れる為に
永遠の真実さえ
eien no shinjitsu sae miushinau
people lose sight of the eternal truth.
見失う
消えない悲しい明日に
kienai kanashii asu ni hikari wo kureta no wa daredemo naku tatta hitori
No one made me realize that there is a light that never dims but you,
光をくれたのは
誰でもなく たった一人
過去も未来も
shinjitai
I want to believe.
kako mo mirai mo wakachiaeru zutto
always sharing the past and the future.
分かち合えるずっと
おい 作業しろよ！
Hey! Keep working.
インプットは済んだ
後はパスを解析するだけだ
I'm done inputting the information.
All I need to do is analyze the password.
なあ 何か消えてねーか？
Hey, something's not right.
どうして虎徹の反応が消えてんだよ！
Why is Kotetsu's signal gone?!
うっ はっ
はあ はあ はあ…
あはは
よっしゃー！
All right!
はあ はあ…
うっうっ…
はっ
虎徹さん…
Kotetsu...
次回　TIGER ＆ BUNNY
最終回
Next time on Tiger & Bunny:
Eternal Immortality
See you
See you...